Hey, I'm Eric Kennedy, and welcome to
Learn UI Design, the complete online
1034711676
video course and resource library.
3095450486
3446427971
You now have lifetime access to the most
3691256008
practical online design curriculum on the
planet, so congratulations.
3882282336
practical online design curriculum on the
planet, so congratulations.
3509809685
I want to take just a couple moments and
talk a little bit about what is in this course.
3724658209
I want to take just a couple moments and
talk a little bit about what is in this course.
3473840942
And normally, I don't love soft intro
content like this, but there's a point
3641764295
And normally, I don't love soft intro
content like this, but there's a point
377225914
here, because Learn UI Design has a
different and opinionated take on how to
4102378802
here, because Learn UI Design has a
different and opinionated take on how to
3624984541
teach user interface design.
1958195869
And while there's over 5 ,000 students in
2618675502
this course, including from basically
every single industry leading company out
1662114319
this course, including from basically
every single industry leading company out
1922906885
there, the explanations and the
frameworks in this course differ quite a
1906093332
there, the explanations and the
frameworks in this course differ quite a
2146751782
bit from what I would call mainstream
design curriculum.
1223808706
The overarching message of Learn UI
Design is this, beautiful, high -quality
2754636507
The overarching message of Learn UI
Design is this, beautiful, high -quality
3353065192
interface design, as much as it might
feel subjective or arbitrary or magic, is not.
2402654512
interface design, as much as it might
feel subjective or arbitrary or magic, is not.
3051444513
It's actually based in logic and rationale.
1466621555
3347031966
And very importantly, that logic is learnable.
1352739043
Now, here is a briefest of overviews of
how we learn this logic throughout this course.
1166416591
Now, here is a briefest of overviews of
how we learn this logic throughout this course.
271545756
Right now, we're in the introduction unit.
1387990604
1248864938
That's where we talk about setting up
460040911
your workspace, as well as getting your
mindset right.
385861082
And this is really all about laying the
groundwork so that you can design
3318966487
And this is really all about laying the
groundwork so that you can design
2878036591
confidently and quickly down the road.
3066426400
The second unit is the fundamentals, and
906867974
1493450840
these are the skills that you're going to
use in every single design that you ever
2928388761
do, whether it's something that merely
needs to be kind of neat and clean and
2372840480
do, whether it's something that merely
needs to be kind of neat and clean and
3477976493
simple, which I call low -brand, or it's
something that needs to be visually much
396953343
simple, which I call low -brand, or it's
something that needs to be visually much
1381385971
more opinionated and outspoken and full
of style, which I call high -brand.
1191457758
So what are those fundamental skills you
use from low -brand to high -brand?
796810537
So what are those fundamental skills you
use from low -brand to high -brand?
3356548065
It's things like alignment, whitespace,
consistency, sizing, etc.
2011770962
It's things like alignment, whitespace,
consistency, sizing, etc.
593361047
The fundamentals unit culminates with a
lesson called the Six Strategies of
1187388919
The fundamentals unit culminates with a
lesson called the Six Strategies of
3306347290
Simplicity, which sort of builds on
everything you've learned in the unit
3155009196
thus far and caps it off with a master
algorithm for building clean, simple designs.
766673417
thus far and caps it off with a master
algorithm for building clean, simple designs.
2342385146
Now, once you're at the point where you
can reliably create clean and simple
3625925359
Now, once you're at the point where you
can reliably create clean and simple
273813585
designs, you might run into this problem,
which is that they look neat, they look
1375384360
designs, you might run into this problem,
which is that they look neat, they look
2993690911
modern, they look organized, but they're
kind of boring.
3481399392
And while that's a great problem to have,
it's still a problem.
1948655137
And while that's a great problem to have,
it's still a problem.
3314800615
So in the next three units, we start
talking about a solution.
725778823
So in the next three units, we start
talking about a solution.
3875847834
And the solution to this is you need to
get good at translating between your
2239076473
brand and your interface.
679296089
1009132178
Now, brand is sort of a catch -all term
3271359501
for the adjectives or phrases or however
you would want your viewer to describe
1119244971
for the adjectives or phrases or however
you would want your viewer to describe
3468201076
your site or business or application.
2104780655
3731303015
And when you're translating your brand
4273273364
into an interface, there's really three
main levers that you're going to pull on
3263295654
into an interface, there's really three
main levers that you're going to pull on
3558189945
in order to do this.
1265738179
They are color, typography, and imagery.
998909419
And lo and behold, those are the next
three units of LearnUI Design.
3419035000
Color is the easiest of these areas to
gain proficiency in, and that
3204847218
Color is the easiest of these areas to
gain proficiency in, and that
193004542
's because every single color is
comprised of just three numbers.
1905436555
If something is made of numbers, it can
be very easy to see the patterns in it.
981996030
If something is made of numbers, it can
be very easy to see the patterns in it.
2595898964
Now, I like to think of color as being
comprised of several sub -skills which
4171244643
Now, I like to think of color as being
comprised of several sub -skills which
211405109
kind of build out on top of each other,
like three concentric circles.
3260087924
kind of build out on top of each other,
like three concentric circles.
3912622300
The innermost skill is working with zero
colors, that is black and white or gray scale.
783683349
Many projects and many brands use only
gray scale anyways, so this is already
1173141311
Many projects and many brands use only
gray scale anyways, so this is already
113093727
useful in its own right.
2274781025
But it's also a critical building block
2380656189
2055749513
for the next skill, which is working with
one color or, in particular, variations
3471024419
on one theme color.
1724016418
860141213
And it's extremely common for a fairly
3383103803
low brand site to have basically nothing
but gray scale, maybe some imagery, and
2094608785
low brand site to have basically nothing
but gray scale, maybe some imagery, and
3863483416
then variations on this one base color.
85596708
The idea of creating variations on a base
4124975347
899524398
color actually informs how we approach
all the rest of color, gradients, dark
1733289098
color actually informs how we approach
all the rest of color, gradients, dark
2501624247
UI, fixing clashing color, etc.
2023410248
Now, the final color skill is working
556877836
4184372212
with many colors, that is, working with a palette.
3686508549
But despite the fact that there's
1189678427
billions of possibilities for this, I
find that so many good palettes really
91756419
billions of possibilities for this, I
find that so many good palettes really
1929570747
fall into one of four different
categories, and I call these the
1857441076
fall into one of four different
categories, and I call these the
2643990510
archetypal palettes.
1249726313
I present them in this course and allow
3487103404
you to use them as sort of a building
block for exploring other interesting
981128979
you to use them as sort of a building
block for exploring other interesting
4285811588
palette ideas.
1727697606
Typography is significantly more complex
1299621989
than color because, unlike color, you
can't boil down a font and how you use it
586591362
than color because, unlike color, you
can't boil down a font and how you use it
1877343878
into just a couple numbers.
654873344
1473024791
And so we take a skill -based approach
3242626231
instead, and I'm fond of saying that in
UI typography, there's really only two
567364916
instead, and I'm fond of saying that in
UI typography, there's really only two
239058141
fundamental skills, choosing good fonts
and styling them well.
1111408573
Have you noticed, by the way, that I'm
always breaking things down into skills
459300585
Have you noticed, by the way, that I'm
always breaking things down into skills
4111288345
and subskills?
1938088674
I promise, this is not accidental.
1005806429
It's actually for your benefit.
3079862887
874993623
And the idea here is that if you're
295299475
totally overwhelmed by typography,
knowing that there's sort of a structure
251328511
totally overwhelmed by typography,
knowing that there's sort of a structure
3685663687
in which everything fits together will be
a huge boon.
4191721631
It'll be a sigh of relief because you can
chip away at those skills one at a time.
2754072137
It'll be a sigh of relief because you can
chip away at those skills one at a time.
1443467578
But even if you're fairly experienced,
knowing how things are broken down allows
2385663865
But even if you're fairly experienced,
knowing how things are broken down allows
1372736797
you to go to where your weaknesses are
and really shore those up and continue to
408979855
learn efficiently.
2715707349
1962756396
Now, as I was saying, there's really just
3277302314
two main subskills to typography and UI
design, choosing good fonts and styling
640316717
two main subskills to typography and UI
design, choosing good fonts and styling
945540914
them well.
2470913292
And choosing good fonts is actually
3397572157
fairly easy to hack, which means you can
get quite good at it without really
3143983943
fairly easy to hack, which means you can
get quite good at it without really
4054522451
deeply understanding what's going on
underneath the surface.
2141918074
That's why, for instance, you have access
to the good fonts table.
950828436
That's why, for instance, you have access
to the good fonts table.
1177068987
And this is a Figma resource.
1355174184
I use it all the time in my own design practice.
1176565218
2300543233
And it's a database of over 100 high
quality, free or very cheap fonts.
3192314273
And it's a database of over 100 high
quality, free or very cheap fonts.
2444245317
They're categorized by type, by brand,
and they're listed with features, usage
704342387
notes and links.
942188664
However, for higher brand sites, it does
3525403700
4105534841
become necessary to start to understand
how a specific font portrays a specific brand.
2379913093
become necessary to start to understand
how a specific font portrays a specific brand.
2171438281
And in Learn UI Design, I really take the
approach that a font is just a set of
3178497581
And in Learn UI Design, I really take the
approach that a font is just a set of
796466342
mildly complex shapes that match each other.
415068171
They go together.
3013733595
And so any statement about how a font
feels or what sort of mood it's trying to
3336065362
And so any statement about how a font
feels or what sort of mood it's trying to
351980680
evoke is really just a statement about shapes.
2418329896
3063770389
And so if you can identify shapes, then
1744500770
you can also identify a fonts brand.
23719324
It's going to be great.
917761276
952017719
Now, styling fonts well is perhaps even
more open -ended than choosing fonts, but
1496995804
we break it down into three areas.
2677899244
1779511432
The first is typographic rules, which you
4241156447
should basically always be following.
3145604122
The second is heuristics or rules of
153157859
2125525923
thumb, to bear in mind as you design with type.
3602131668
And then the third is common
1562773033
1614961307
typographical design patterns.
2794164190
These are things that just pop up time
1902412667
and time again in high quality,
professional type work.
2594874988
and time again in high quality,
professional type work.
1473475165
Overall, this will allow us to take the
deepest and most complex part of UI
3624148081
design and make it tractable and logical.
2852914533
1577167394
Now, from there, we'll move on to Unit 5,
3821185987
where we talk about imagery and other
components or elements that appear in
1576158204
where we talk about imagery and other
components or elements that appear in
554244422
your UI.
1267108487
And we're going to cover the three main
3802122668
types of imagery that appear in UI,
photography, illustrations, and icons, as
1500973310
types of imagery that appear in UI,
photography, illustrations, and icons, as
338237387
well as the different sorts of components
that appear in design systems, buttons,
2584508163
well as the different sorts of components
that appear in design systems, buttons,
2979295421
text boxes, dropdowns, radio buttons, etc.
2816919940
There's more in this unit too, but that's
2774760999
292137973
a gist of it.
2419160613
And all the while, we'll be focusing not
342651348
only on how do you make these elements
look great, but also how do you make them
93462881
only on how do you make these elements
look great, but also how do you make them
2136542779
match the brand that you're trying to achieve?
3586839272
From there, we're going to move on to
2098943823
Unit 6, which is digital platforms and paradigms.
2420222013
1052509155
And this is about all of the sort of
3075744689
specific concerns that come up doing
digital design.
2011050330
specific concerns that come up doing
digital design.
3017177408
It's everything from accessibility to
responsive design, to the idiosyncrasies
3357205280
It's everything from accessibility to
responsive design, to the idiosyncrasies
3232287907
of iOS or Android design.
80519654
The final unit is communicating design.
2722614252
And there, we're going to talk about all
the times where you need to present your
3585595520
And there, we're going to talk about all
the times where you need to present your
1911222312
work to others in any capacity.
4247339743
Maybe it's giving a design presentation
3547105703
1433593492
and getting feedback.
2510675038
Maybe it's the developer handoff,
2750372785
creating a design portfolio, even design interviews.
1801609550
1602094110
It's all in there.
156951684
999829180
It's all in there.
243024850
By and large, you can watch these lessons
in any order you prefer.
1866634312
By and large, you can watch these lessons
in any order you prefer.
3599295499
So you can go through them straight
through, no problem there, or you can
1328609580
skip around to whatever skills you'd like
to improve on first.
1312696775
skip around to whatever skills you'd like
to improve on first.
2326857270
The second note is you can also adjust
the speed as desired, because seeing as
2870672150
The second note is you can also adjust
the speed as desired, because seeing as
2040419379
though this course is over 35 hours of
video content, I understand that that is
799796644
a lot.
67390650
Just use the little gear icon below to
2988502203
3059923808
switch to 1 .5x or 2x, and you can watch
or review anything much faster than just 1x.
1319664866
switch to 1 .5x or 2x, and you can watch
or review anything much faster than just 1x.
651862822
Third, you have lifetime access.
1805165457
Please don't feel like this course is a sprint.
3164720673
672831008
I want this course to be a lifetime
resource that you can refer to again and again.
3309755763
I want this course to be a lifetime
resource that you can refer to again and again.
1060811123
And each time you dive into a video,
whether it's for the first time or
224274653
subsequent times, you learn something
new, just like talking to a knowledgeable
4217099721
subsequent times, you learn something
new, just like talking to a knowledgeable
3803742203
friend would do.
4257420762
1591677416
friend would do.
2980982842
3659872613
And finally, I should mention, there's
579668468
really only one software requirement for
this course, which is you need a UI
1758739234
really only one software requirement for
this course, which is you need a UI
2053606054
design app.
4223239190
I recommend Figma, which is the industry
2219881108
standard and what I use for my own day
-to -day design work, but Learn UI Design
428667315
standard and what I use for my own day
-to -day design work, but Learn UI Design
425106566
is not a course about a specific tool.
3254860661
It's a course about more underlying and
443898408
2696067760
unchanging principles of beautiful
design, and you can use whichever tool
2481032600
you feel most comfortable with.
2280006211
1846653850
It should be clear by now, but Learn UI
2996996220
Design is all about visual design.
2358218
1967305257
I do have two other courses, Learn UX
2218724545
Design, which is about making software
simple and usable.
4096486220
Design, which is about making software
simple and usable.
2180552213
It covers user research, usability
testing, wire framing, and heuristics for
2848193903
It covers user research, usability
testing, wire framing, and heuristics for
419749722
just creating simple, intuitive apps, and
then Landing Page Academy, which is about
3928723162
doing the copywriting for high converting
landing pages and making them look spectacular.
2752912006
doing the copywriting for high converting
landing pages and making them look spectacular.
4240731504
doing the copywriting for high converting
landing pages and making them look spectacular.
2202148771
Finally, I want to say this.
769003829
One thing that we've seen replicate again
2045237212
and again in the science of education is
that the more you grapple with the
3130276404
and again in the science of education is
that the more you grapple with the
3374532424
knowledge you're trying to learn, the
more you try and apply it in different
886841974
ways and in live practice, even though
that can be much more challenging than
2305960343
ways and in live practice, even though
that can be much more challenging than
2891589611
just sitting back and watching some
videos, it will help you learn it better
3252581315
just sitting back and watching some
videos, it will help you learn it better
2207056906
and remember it longer.
3572100821
3527535791
If you do that, you will build your
3326977527
design instinct.
2960922674
You will get better at describing design.
3715701067
3746580591
You may understand something about how to
fix some designs, but you will not really
2727175133
You may understand something about how to
fix some designs, but you will not really
1576191492
improve at actually designing.
1747172099
If you want to improve at actually
3099906305
designing, you need to actually design,
and there are a couple ways that you can
147182109
designing, you need to actually design,
and there are a couple ways that you can
4089740707
do this.
4205577697
2924081321
do this.
4177329138
For instance, in the alignment lesson,
264400438
3149814162
you can go practice alignment without
having to worry about color and
3571040931
you can go practice alignment without
having to worry about color and
2191541043
typography and all the rest.
1076412441
I also highly encourage you to work on
3624784344
your own project while going through this
course, because the more hiccups you run
1293721154
your own project while going through this
course, because the more hiccups you run
1981100723
into in your design process, the more
opportunities there are for you to have
1519755239
into in your design process, the more
opportunities there are for you to have
1547997857
an aha moment watching these videos in
the near future.
3525574425
an aha moment watching these videos in
the near future.
148128852
Despite my insistence and encouragement
that you kind of struggle with the
930073740
Despite my insistence and encouragement
that you kind of struggle with the
2157421145
design, you grapple with it a little bit,
I don't want you to burn out.
3655768809
And so what I will say from my own
experience is that whenever you start to
3544716916
And so what I will say from my own
experience is that whenever you start to
1086322288
feel like you're kind of just spinning
your wheels on design and you're stuck,
2161793418
feel like you're kind of just spinning
your wheels on design and you're stuck,
1283734085
get feedback from a knowledgeable professional.
1173507885
3823223067
get feedback from a knowledgeable professional.
1773975723
You can find another experienced designer
2851318727
and ask them for some advice, but in my
own experience, getting good feedback
489687467
and ask them for some advice, but in my
own experience, getting good feedback
879702346
just cuts through the noise so well and
is a much better use of time than just
2455857269
just cuts through the noise so well and
is a much better use of time than just
3484439663
kind of grinding your gears and getting discouraged.
554502777
Okay, now your homework for this, the
337832509
467091750
very first lesson, is to do a baseline design.
1940588749
1121523577
very first lesson, is to do a baseline design.
683842053
So what you do here is you get a baseline
165042300
sense of where you're at when beginning
this course, and then at the end of the
488740539
sense of where you're at when beginning
this course, and then at the end of the
2763845791
course, you can redesign these screens
and get a sense of what you've learned.
2523010069
As with all the homework assignments in
this course, you can scroll down to the
226546223
As with all the homework assignments in
this course, you can scroll down to the
3486295013
homework subhead below and read about it there.
1123853056
And that covers it for the intro lesson.
3877227606
2707456924
So whichever lesson you proceed to next,
I just want to say thank you again for
975929780
So whichever lesson you proceed to next,
I just want to say thank you again for
581248761
enrolling in Learn UI Design, and I wish
you all the best on your design journey.